# 今天我们把这个公鸡把它剁了
Today we are going to chop this rooster
# 是个我们这里的土鸡
This is our own free range chicken
# 我们先把它剁一下
Let’s chop a big cut
# 剁鸡也是从中间开始剁
Chop the chicken into pieces from the middle
# 一般烧的鸡我们就剁大块一点
Since we are going to braise the chicken we can chop them into bigger pieces
# 大家可以看一下这两个是鸡的腰子 据说是大补
Let’s take a look, this is the chicken’s kidneys, I heard they are very nutritious
# 然后就不用改刀 改了刀它就烂了
And then no need to cut it, otherwise it will dissolve in the stew
# 就直接放在里面一起烧
Just dump them into the stew
# 这个是它的消化的东西
This is what the chicken digested
# 切这个鸡胗的时候不要切这边 这边是筋
Don’t cut this side of the chicken gizzard while slicing it, this side is the tendon
# 你必须切这一面它才会散花 才会这样子散开
You need to slice this side, so it will shrink and spread out like this
# 切这一面是不会散开的
Slicing from this side will not spread out
# 而且切这一面非常的丑
And it will look very ugly if slicing from this side
# 然后我们一刀一刀地切下去 不要切断
Now we are slicing it slowly, don’t cut through
# 刚好切到那一面白色的位置
Stop slicing when you reach the white part
# 看到没中间是白色的东西
You see this white strip in the middle
# 然后再横过来再切 切进去
Then turn it and slice again
# 待会儿它熟了过后这个就收缩起来像一朵花一样
Once it’s cooked it will shrink and spread out like flower blossom
# 这个鸡胗这样子切出来口感非常的好
Cut the gizzard this way the texture will be satisfying
# 四伯爷 你看
Uncle Four, check it out
# 跟汤圆儿一样噶
They look like Tangyuan
# 人家不晓得的以为这个是鸡蛋 以为这个是土鸡蛋
People who don’t know might think these are eggs, they might think these are our farm eggs
# 看到没 还有这个白的
You see this one, it’s white
# 大家看得到吗 这个小土豆
Let’s see, this is mini potato
# 然后这个是芋头 小芋头
And this one is taro, mini taro
# 待会儿烧公鸡就用这个来烧
We will braise the rooster with these
# 这个大蒜就对半切 切了煮一下方便你们等会儿拈来吃
We are cutting the garlic in half, easier to grab to eat later
# 这蒜整耙了好干（吃）
You gotta cook the garlic soft for it to taste good
# 这个吃辣点跟中辣两个 吃特辣就要冬天越辣越安逸
We normally eat two type of spicy, medium hot and extra spicy, it's better to eat extra spicy in winter, the spicier dishes are in winter, the more comfortable we are
# 这个时候安 吃中辣是最合适的
This time of the year, medium hot is the best
# 四伯爷还会吃安
Uncle Four you know your food
# 要根据天气
Gotta eat according to the weather
# 我说你还多会吃安
That’s why I said you know your food
# 嗨 这些东西都想不到啊
Oh well there are many things you can’t even think of
# 诶 好久你又做泡海椒安
Oh when are you making pickled chili pepper
# 要下半年去了都嘛
Later half of the year
# 下半年去了噶 下半年我们一起做嘛
Okay, later, later we can make it together
# 撒点香菜就可以吃了
Garnish with some cilantro we can eat it now
# 这个土豆你看 筷子都夹得耙
Check out this potatoes, it’s soft that I can cut it in half with my chopsticks
# 你想嘛 是你师父亲自做得咋不好吃嘛
Think about it, your teacher made this himself, how can it be bad
# 看 我们这个土豆（好软）
See, this potato is so soft
# 等我学会了我做给你吃四伯爷
When I learn how to cook this I will make it for you Uncle Four
# 好嘛好嘛 你把技术学都来做给我吃嘛
Okay fine, learn the skill and cook for me
# 你跟你师父两个比哈嘛
And compete with your teacher
# 我才不跟他比呢 我不敢
I am not going to compete with him, I don’t think I can
# 不敢哇
I am too scared to
# 我不配
I do not deserve to
# 你学会了还是可以
If you learn how to cook you can
# 下次你整点土豆烧点排骨跟我吃嘛
Next time can you braise some potatoes with ribs for me
# 要得啊
Sure
# 那个东西烧起还不是好吃啊 安逸得很
Braising those together is very tasty, feel good about it
# 弄个子四伯爷 二回你出排骨我出土豆 嘿嘿
Next time Uncle Four, you provide ribs I will provide potatoes, how about that
# 要的啊 我们两爷子我吃点亏不关事的
Sure, it doesn’t matter if we rip each other off a little
# 我们吃排骨不吃亏
We are getting ripped off If we are getting ribs to eat
# 我出嘴巴就要得了哈四伯爷
I am just gonna provide my mouth
# 好
Sure
# 土鸡是不一样
Free range chicken is really different
# 三黄鸡 二代鸡都没得这个土鸡好吃
Yeah, neither yellow chicken nor hybrid chicken(farm/industrial) is as good as this free range chicken
# 嗯 这个芋头比土豆好吃
This taro is tastier than the potatoes
# 真的啊 我没尝
Oh really, I haven’t tried yet